我叫巴里·艾伦  是现今世上速度最快的人
My name is Barry Allen, and I am the fastest man alive.
我年幼时  看到自己的母亲
When I was a child, I saw my mother killed
被令人难以置信的东西杀害
by something impossible.
快跑  巴里
Run, Barry, run!
我父亲因为谋杀母亲进了监狱
My father went to prison for her murder.
但是一场事故让我也变得令人难以置信
Then an accident made me the impossible.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但我秘密地用自己的速度打击犯罪
but secretly, I use my speed to fight crime
寻找跟我一样的人
and find others like me.
终有一天  我会找到杀害母亲的凶手
And one day, I'll find who killed my mother...
妈妈
Mom!
让我父亲沉冤得雪
And get justice for my father.
我就是  闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on The Flash...
爱瑞丝·韦斯特
Iris West.
艾迪
Eddie.
黄衣人带走了艾迪
The Man in Yellow, he took Eddie.
我保证会找到他的
I promise I'll find him, okay?
巴里
Barry.
想想你最好的朋友
Think about your best friend.
可能是你的妻子  你的父亲
It could be your wife, your father,
也许是某个和你一起长大的人
maybe someone you grew up with.
是那个你等不及要在一天结束后
It's the person you can't wait to talk to
与其谈心的人
at the end of the day.
那个知道你所有的秘密
The person who knows everything about you,
支持着你的人
who roots for you.
现在  想象你这最好的朋友有个秘密
Now imagine you discover your best friend has a secret.
不  不是一个
No, not a secret.
是一堆秘密
A universe of secrets.
你会正面和他对质吗
Would you confront him?
还是会保持沉默
Would you stay silent?
不管怎样  你知道一切都不会再如从前
Either way, you know nothing will ever be the same again.
中城警局
斯旺在哪
Where is Thawne?
他请假了
He took some personal time.
是啊  艾迪最近有很多事  队长
Yeah, Eddie's been going through some stuff, Captain.
谁的生活不是一堆事啊
Yeah, aren't we all?
这些金店劫匪调查的怎么样了
You got anything on these gold store robberies?
他们上周又抢了两家店
Perps hit up two more in the last week,
咱们却什么线索都没有
and we still got nothing.
我们正在办
We're working on it.
我们还在等实验室出结果
Just waiting on some final results from the lab.
好吧  加快速度
All right, well, pick up the pace.
然后看看能不能联系到闪电侠
And see if somebody can contact The Flash.
也许他能帮我们加快点速度
Maybe he can help speed things up.
你知道我是什么意思
You know what I mean.
快去吧
Get going.
-有线索吗  -没有
- Anything? - No.
我所有地方都找过了
I mean, I've looked everywhere.
继续找
Keep looking.
当然
Of course. Yeah.
我正要出去呢  有事吗
Uh, I'm heading out right now.  What's up?
发生了一件事
Something happened.
我本不应该随便说的
And I'm not supposed to say anything,
但我实在是忍不住
but I couldn't keep quiet.
怎么了
What happened?
那个黄衣人
The Man in Yellow,
他从我面前抓走了艾迪
he took Eddie right in front of me.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
不不  一点也不好
No, no. Not at all.
-不是  我  -闪电侠也在那
- No, I... - The Flash was there.
他让我回家  不要告诉任何人
He told me to go home and not to talk to anyone
因为他会解决这件事  但是他没有
because he would fix it, but he hasn't.
我认为警察应该出去搜寻艾迪
I think the police should be out there searching for Eddie.
不  爱瑞丝
No, Iris--
我父亲需要知道真相
My dad needs to know the truth.
我觉得闪电侠说得对
I think that The Flash is right.
乔和警察们  他们打不过
Joe and the cops, they're no match
那个黄衣人  爱瑞丝
for The Man in Yellow, Iris.
他们只会徒然受伤
They would just get hurt.
所以你觉得闪电侠现在正在外边
So you think The Flash is out there right now,
寻找艾迪呢吗
searching for Eddie?
我肯定他在尽一切努力找到他
I'm sure he's doing everything he can to find him.
是  不过我现在感觉
Yeah, well, I'm finding it pretty hard
很难信任闪电侠了
to trust The Flash right now.
那就信任我
Well, then, trust me.
好吗
Okay?
很抱歉发生了这一切  我...
Look, I'm so sorry about all of this. I...
一切都会好的
Everything is gonna be okay.
我得走了
I have to go.
趴下
Get down!
你准备留着这些威尔斯用来
You planning on keeping all those cameras
监视咱们的摄像头吗
Wells used to spy on us?
感觉背后发麻  你不觉得吗
That's kind of creepy, don't you think?
机械工程学第一守则  伙计
First rule of mechanical engineering, dude.
永远不要浪费好东西
Never waste good tech.
中城黄金储蓄所
中城黄金储蓄所遭到了攻击
Central City Gold Reserve's under attack.
黄金  那是辛格想让我们查的案子
Gold? That's the case Singh wants us on.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
今天这日子选的不好啊  伙计
You picked a bad day for this, pal.
怎么回事
What was that?
你的眼球运动很正常
Your eye movement is normal.
没有神经损伤的迹象
No signs of neurological damage.
你觉得那劫匪
Do you think the thief
会不会是个超能力者
might have been a meta-human
用神秘力量扰乱了你什么的
who put the whammie on you or something?
我不知道
I-I don't know.
当彩虹大盗影响我大脑的时候
When Rainbow Raider got in my head,
我能感觉到的只有愤怒
all I felt was anger.
但这不一样
But this was not that.
这个只有不断的恐惧
This was just overwhelming fear.
看起来你倒下的时候
Looks like when you went down,
那劫匪也混乱了
the thief got disoriented too.
也许我们都被扰乱了
Maybe we both got whammied.
那你也了解这感觉了
Then you know how it feels.
你好  巴里
Hi, Barry.
或者我该叫你闪电侠
Or should I say The Flash?
闪电侠  第一季二十一集
这是少数几次
This is one of the few times
我不想当巴里·艾伦的时刻之一
I would not want to be Barry Allen.
我好奇他会怎么说
I wonder what he's gonna say.
我们绝对不应该去偷听
We should absolutely not listen in.
这确实不关我们的事
It's none of our business.
但是闪电侠与我们有关
But The Flash is our business.
而爱瑞丝刚发现巴里是闪电侠
And Iris did just find out that Barry's The Flash.
所以联系起来
So by transitive property,
巴里和艾瑞丝就是我们的事了
Barry and Iris are our business.
我  等下  你是怎么发现的
I--Wait. How did you find out?
那晚我触到闪电侠时
When I touched The Flash the other night,
我感觉到了电流
I felt a jolt of electricity.
我唯一一次感觉到这种电流
The only other time I have ever felt anything like that
是事故后你昏迷时
was when you were in a coma after the accident.
真不敢相信我居然没能早点发现
I can't believe I didn't figure it out sooner.
我都想象不出你现在有多生气
I can only imagine how angry you are.
我不生气  巴里
I'm not angry, Barry.
只是很失望
I'm just disappointed.
好吧
Okay.
艾迪知道吗
Does Eddie know?
知道
Yes, he does.
所以他才被绑架吗
Is that why he got kidnapped?
不  我也不知道威尔斯为什么抓走艾迪
No, I don't know why Wells took Eddie. I--
威尔斯博士就是黄衣人
Dr. Wells is The Man in Yellow?
他所做的一切  对我的帮助
Everything he's been doing, helping me...
都是假的
it was all a lie.
威尔斯杀了我妈妈
Wells killed my mom.
-他会杀掉艾迪吗  -不  不会
- Is he gonna kill Eddie? - No, he's not.
我会把艾迪救回来的  我发誓
I'm gonna get Eddie back, I swear.
嗯  闪电侠也是这么说的
Yeah, The Flash said the same thing.
爱瑞丝  请你相信我  我
Look, Iris, you have to believe me, I--
有太多次我都想直接告诉你
There were so many times I wanted to tell you.
我第一个就想告诉你
You are the first person I wanted to tell,
但事情越来越疯狂
but everything started getting crazy,
然后我就想也许乔是对的  我不该
and I thought maybe Joe was right and I shouldn't say--
等等
Wait, wait, wait.
你是说我爸爸一直都知道
You're telling me that my dad knew
却不让你告诉我
and he told you not to tell me?
他是想保护你
He was trying to protect you.
我们都是
We both were.
也许你俩不该继续保护我了
Yeah, well, maybe it's time you both stopped.
喂
Yeah,
嗯  我们还需要一批
Yeah, if we could get another shipment of the, uh,
电脑
computers in here...
我发现这事好像不是我们该管的
Yeah, I don't think that had anything to do with us.
没错
Nope.
你应该没带午餐来吧
Don't suppose you brought lunch?
你知道不知道人类有
Did you know that human beings
两个月不进食
can survive up to two months
还活下来的先例
without food?
你就打算把我关在这里那么久吗
Is that how long you're planning on keeping me here?
其实
You know...
恐怕到不了那么久
I doubt it'll come to that.
能告诉我我们为什么在这里吗
You want to tell me what we're doing down here?
不能
No.
你说我们是亲戚  说你来自未来
You told me we're related, that you're from the future.
证明一下
Prove it.
我不需要给任何人证明任何事
Yeah, I don't have to prove anything to anyone.
我觉得你就是个大骗子
Well, I think you're full of crap.
不管你到底想做什么
And whatever you're trying to do,
你都不会得逞的  因为闪电侠他
you're not gonna get away with it because The Flash is--
闭嘴
Stop talking.
博士被控杀妻
黄衣人
听说你和巴里谈过了
I heard you talked to Barry.
这就是所谓的闭门羹了吧
So this is what my cold shoulder treatment feels like.
听着
Look...
宝贝  我的做法  也许
baby, the way I went about things, maybe--
不  我确实做错了
No. I was wrong.
我只是想保护你
I was just trying to keep you safe.
这个借口已经快用烂了
You know, that excuse is getting really old.
先是报警校的事
First it was the police academy,
然后是和艾迪恋爱的事  现在又是这个
and then it was dating Eddie, and now this.
宝贝  你知道黄衣人会做出什么样的事
Sweetheart, you know what The Man in Yellow is capable of.
他杀过警察  他杀了梅森·布里奇
He killed cops. He killed Mason Bridge.
梅森是威尔斯杀的
Wells killed Mason?
你居然隐瞒了这件事
And you're covering that up?
不不不
No. No. No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
如果让人们知道了威尔斯的事
If the world finds out about Wells,
他们就会知道巴里的身份了
they find out about Barry.
我也想保护他
I'm trying to keep him safe too.
你就从来没想过也许告诉我实情
Did you ever stop to think that looping me in
才真的是在保护我吗
would keep me safe?
也许如果我知道到底是怎么回事
That if I knew what was going on out there,
也许能有所准备
I could prepare for it?
也许我能帮你和巴里抓坏人
Maybe I could've helped you and Barry put the bad guys away
而不是阻碍你们
instead of being in the way.
相信我  我也一直在思考这个问题
Believe me, I asked myself that question every single day.
每次你的博客有了
Every time you posted something new
关于闪电侠的新发布
about The Flash on your blog--
爸  我说的不只是巴里是闪电侠的事
Dad, it's not just about Barry being The Flash.
你知道他对我的感情有多久
You knew how he felt about me for God knows how long,
你也没有告诉我
and you didn't tell me that either.
那种事我不能插手  爱瑞丝
That wasn't for me to tell, Iris.
如果你们有任何一个人跟我说了实情
Well, you know what, if any of you had been honest with me,
也许艾迪就不会出事了
maybe Eddie would still be here.
要不是我和他开始约会他也不会被
He wouldn't have gotten involved in all of this
卷入此事
if I hadn't been dating him.
你是说如果你早知道巴里对你的感情
Are you saying if you had known how Barry felt--
我是在说艾迪出事完全是
What I am saying is that what happened to Eddie
你的错
is your fault.
工作电话
This is work.
我们可以继续这个谈话
We can finish this talk.
谈话
Talking.
真新奇啊
Yeah, that'll be new.
喂  老大
Yeah, boss?
乔刚来了电话
I just got a call from Joe.
中城黄金储蓄所将要给海滨城金库
The Central City Gold Reserve is about to transport
运送价值三亿的金条
$300 million in gold bars to their Coast City vault.
辛格告诉乔他们认为戴面具的人
Singh told Joe they think the man in the mask
会去劫车
is gonna make a play for it.
好吧  但是我们还不确定你看到的幻象
Okay, but we still don't know if he's responsible
是不是他引起的呢
for those weird images you saw.
他们要怎么运送金条
How are they transporting the gold?
冰淇淋
抱歉  冰淇淋卖完了
Sorry, no more ice cream.
但你的音乐还在放啊
But your music's playing.
没错  意思就是卖完了
Yeah, it means we're out.
走吧
Come on.
你还是把音乐关掉吧
You might want to kill the music.
劫犯来的时候可不能有孩子在周围
We don't want any kids around if our thief shows up.
货车中了地雷
The truck just got hit by a land mine.
乔没事吧
Is Joe okay?
还不确定
We don't know yet.
不许动  放下武器
Freeze! Drop your weapon!
别逼我
Don't make me do this.
没事吧
You okay?
嗯  你呢
Yeah. You?
不想让你再打他一枪了
I didn't want you to have to shoot him again.
我今天过得不怎么样
And I'm having a pretty bad day.
所以就是他吗
So is this guy.
我们来看看金手指有什么可说的
Let's see what Goldfinger has to say for himself.
艾林将军
General Eiling?
他是怎么回事
What is wrong with him?
我从他的肩上挖出一颗子弹
I pulled a bullet out of his shoulder.
本该疼到不行
Which should hurt like hell.
而他好像根本没感觉到
And it didn't even seem like he felt it.
我给他做了全身扫描  除此之外
I did a complete body scan, and otherwise,
艾林将军身体非常健康
General Eiling is perfectly healthy.
那他为什么像个机器人似的站在那
So why is he just standing there like a robot?
我刚和天眼会通了电话
I just got off the phone with Argus.
官方说法是 艾林正在行政休假
Officially, Eiling is on administrative leave.
非官方的呢
Unofficially?
我和狄格尔的妻子莱拉聊过了
I spoke with Diggle's wife, Lyla,
她说艾林已经
and she said Eiling's been missing
失踪三个月了
for the past three months
而天眼会一直在瞒着这事
and Argus is covering up for it.
倒说得通
Makes sense.
我最后一次见到将军
Last time I saw the general
是在我和罗尼把斯泰因教授
was when Ronnie and I broke Professor Stein
从那个军事机构里救出来的时候
out of that military facility.
我相信他们也把那件事瞒起来了
I'm sure they're covering that up too.
所以那他在此之后又在哪儿呢
So where has he been since then?
艾林将军  你为什么要抢劫黄金储蓄所
General Eiling, why were you trying to rob the gold reserve?
也许他正处于某种催眠状态中
Maybe he's in some kind of a trance?
将军  你记得我吗
General, do you remember me?
闪电侠
Flash.
他怎么知道你是闪电侠的
Whoa, how does he know you're The Flash?
我不知道
I don't know.
将军
General--
艾林不在这儿
Eiling not here.
艾林  坏
Eiling bad.
也许是某种精神崩溃
Maybe it's some kind of psychotic break
以人格分裂症的方式表现出来
presenting itself as dissociative identity disorder.
凯特琳
Caitlin.
凯特琳  好
Caitlin good.
谢谢你
Oh, uh, thank you?
别想着多重性格了
Mm. Forget multiple personalities.
你们看过《驱魔人》吗
You guys have seen The Exorcist, right?
你这个电影狂魔
You and your movies.
继续和他说话
Keep talking to him.
他好像会回答你
He seems to respond to you.
为什么艾林是坏人
Uh, why is Eiling bad?
艾林伤害了我
Eiling hurt me.
我伤害艾林
I hurt Eiling.
好吧  如果你不是艾林
Okay, uh, so if you're not Eiling,
那你是谁
then who are you?
我
I...
是
Am...
古鲁德
Grodd.
颤抖吧
Fear... me.
古鲁德是什么
What is a Grodd?
古鲁德是一只大猩猩
Oh, Grodd is a gorilla.
五年前  艾林和威尔斯正研究一个项目
Five years ago, Eiling and Wells were working on a project
来提高士兵在战斗中的认知能力
to expand soldiers' cognitive abilities during battle.
但我们没想到的是艾林
What we didn't realize is that Eiling
想要创造有通灵能力的战士
was trying to create soldiers with psychic abilities.
"通灵"是什么意思
What do you mean "Psychic"?
艾林试着创造有心灵感应
Eiling was trying to create these super-soldiers
和远距遥控能力的超级士兵
with telepathic and telekinetic capabilities.
但当威尔斯教授发现艾林做的这些
But when Dr. Wells found out about the terrible experiments
可怕的实验时  他终止了整个项目
that Eiling was doing, he shut down the entire project.
所以我们的疯狂杀人犯喜欢小动物
So our psycho-killer has a soft spot for animals.
真暖心啊
That's sweet.
古鲁德发生了什么事
What happened to Grodd?
我们不知道
We don't know.
在粒子加速器爆炸后
After the Particle Accelerator exploded,
我下去看他  而他的笼子是空的
I went down to check on him, and his cage was empty.
所以他可能被影响巴里的
So he could have been affected
同一种能量影响到了
by the same energy that hit Barry?
当暗物质影响到古鲁德时  艾林注射的
When the dark matter hit Grodd, all the drugs and serums
所有药物和血清都可能被激活了
that Eiling injected him with could've activated.
也许加速器的爆炸创造了一个超能力猩猩
Maybe the Accelerator explosion created a meta-gorilla.
我想我们知道当一个
And I think we know what happens
被人类惹火了的超级聪明的猩猩
when a super-intelligent ape who's pissed off at humans
逃脱囚禁后会发生什么
escapes captivity.
西斯科说的第一部分是对的
Cisco's right about the first part.
这是我给古鲁德做的第一次大脑扫描
This is the first brain scan that I did on Grodd.
他的皮质主要运动区和布洛卡区
Whoa. His primary motor cortex and Broca's area
就像圣诞树被点亮了似的
are lit up like a Christmas tree.
受益于艾林的实验
From Eiling's experiments.
而这是我刚刚给艾林做的大脑扫描
And this is the brain scan that I just did on Eiling.
他的大脑被点亮的位置如出一辙
His brain is lit up in the exact same way.
所以古鲁德和艾林以某种方式连在一起了
So Grodd and Eiling are connected somehow?
我觉得古鲁德以某种方式向艾林的
I think that somehow, Grodd is transmitting neural signals
皮质主要运动区传送神经信号
to Eiling's primary motor cortex.
意念控制  心电感应
Mind control, telepathy--
谁知道古鲁德现在能做什么
who knows what Grodd is capable of now?
古鲁德想要什么  复仇吗
What do we think Grodd wants? Revenge?
我不喜欢威尔斯救了古鲁德的这个事实
I do not like the fact that Wells rescued Grodd.
我觉得这只猩猩恰好在
I don't think it's a coincidence
我们想要找威尔斯的时候出现
that this gorilla shows up at the very same time
这不是巧合
we're looking for Wells.
古鲁德和威尔斯确实有特别的感情
Grodd and Wells always did have a special bond.
如果威尔斯利用古鲁德来声东击西
It wouldn't surprise me if Wells was using Grodd
我不会感到意外
to distract us.
如果我们找到古鲁德  就能找到威尔斯
If we find Grodd, we find Wells.
如果我们找到威尔斯
If we find Wells--
就能找到艾迪
We find Eddie.
我要来帮忙
And I'm gonna help.
你懂关于猩猩的知识吗
Know anything about gorillas?
正巧知道呢
I just might.
有报告说某种动物
There have been reports of some sort of animal
在下水道里
down in the sewers.
大鳄鱼  地下怪物
Mm. Alligators. C.H.U.D.S.
异常大的啮齿动物
R.O.U.S.Es?
我是咱们这儿唯一一个看电影的吗
Am I the only one who watches movies around here?
几个月前  两个下水道工人失踪了
Uh, a few months ago, two sewer workers went missing.
城市工人失踪  下水道里的噪音
搜索救援组报告说在地道里
The search party reported hearing
听到了奇怪的类似动物的声音
strange animallike noises down in the tunnels.
他们具体是在哪儿失踪的
Where exactly did they go missing?
第五和第十大道的交叉路口
Uh, Fifth Avenue and Tenth Street.
在那个交叉路口大约向东两条街
There's an access point to the sewers
有一个通往下水道的入口
about two blocks east of that intersection.
我从那儿开始
I'll start there.
别一个人  我也去
Not alone. I'm coming too.
费力地蹚过好一长串的老鼠  蟑螂
Huh, wading through miles of rats, roaches,
还有人类排泄物  别算上我
and human excrement-- count me out.
算上我吧
Count me in.
他是你的猴子了
He's your monkey.
尖端科研实验室
西斯科  拿着剩下的燃烧棒
Cisco, take the rest of these flares,
点亮了  随着咱们边走边放
light them, drop them as we go.
标记我们回去的路
It's our path back.
把香蕉给我
Give me that banana.
好
Okay.
-跟紧点  -没问题
- Stay close. - Definitely.
我哪也不去
Not going anywhere.
谢谢你支持我
Thanks for sticking up for me.
当然
Of course.
不管怎样  巴里骗了你
For what it's worth, Barry feels really terrible
他也很难受
about lying to you.
他应该
He should.
你也骗了我
You lied too.
你的未婚夫
Your fiancée?
罗尼  没错
Ronnie. Yes.
我以为他死于粒子加速器爆炸
Uh, I thought he died in the Particle Accelerator explosion,
可结果他只是...
but turns out he just...
烧了起来
caught on fire.
但是他没事吗
But he's okay?
他没事
Yeah. He is.
那就好  我很高兴
Good. I'm glad.
不敢相信我来这
I can't believe I'm down here
找一只超自然大猩猩
looking for a supernatural gorilla.
普通的大猩猩我都怕
I'm terrified of regular gorillas.
那是什么声音
What was that?
你们来看看这个
Hey, hey, guys, look at this.
太惊人了
Incredible.
看来我们来对地方了
Looks like we're in the right place.
有没有人说说我们在看的是什么
Somebody want to tell me what we're looking at here?
古鲁德
Grodd.
他在进化
He's evolving.
他变得更聪明了
He's getting smarter.
变得更聪明  这下好了
Getting smarter. Great.
如果我没看过《侏罗纪公园》
If I hadn't seen Jurassic Park,
现在就不会这么害怕了
I wouldn't be nearly as frightened right now.
所以如果他变得聪明了
So if he's getting smarter,
你们觉得他的体型也会变得更大吗
you think he might be getting bigger too?
肯定是有辆卡车从上面经过吧
That must have been a truck passing over, right?
西斯科
Cisco?
巴里
Barry!
-我们要离开这里  -巴里失去知觉了
- We got to get out of here. - Barry's out cold.
乔
Joe!
爸爸
Dad!
你要对我做什么
Wh-what are you doing to me?
救命
Help!
西斯科  救救我
Cisco, help me!
这里没人帮你
No help here.
我脑子里能听到你的话  你能心灵感应
I can hear you in my head. You are telepathic.
求你
Please.
求求你
不不不
No, no, no!
父亲讨厌枪
Father hate gun.
父亲
Father.
父亲  你是说威尔斯
Father, you mean-- you mean Wells.
威尔斯  你是说威尔斯吗
Wells? Is that what you mean?
他在哪
Where is he?
不在这里
Not here.
等等  等等  给
Wait, wait, wait. Here.
这是你想要的吗
Is this what you want?
拿去吧
You can have it.
归你了
It's yours.
古鲁德讨厌香蕉
Grodd hate banana.
别杀我
Please, please.
你在经历皮质主要运动区的
You're experiencing a spike of activity
活动飙升
in your primary motor cortex.
和我们在艾林身上看到是一样的
It's the same thing we saw in Eiling.
你看到的图像是古鲁德的某种心灵攻击
The images you saw were some kind of psychic attack by Grodd.
先是艾迪被黄衣人抓走
First Eddie gets taken by The Man in Yellow,
然后是我爸爸
and now my dad--
我们会把他俩都救回来的  爱瑞丝
We're gonna save both of them, Iris.
-我向你保证  -等等
- I promise you. - Hold up.
我在你射进古鲁德的镇静镖里放了追踪器
I put a tracker in the tranq dart you shot Grodd with.
-只要将其激活  -不  西斯科
- As soon as it activates-- - No, Cisco.
我等不了了
I can't wait for that.
必要的话  我会搜索下水道的每个角落
I will search every inch of that sewer if I have to.
如果找到他们了怎么办
And what happens if you find them?
如果古鲁德像控制艾林一样
What happens if Grodd takes over your mind
控制你的大脑怎么办
the same way he did with Eiling?
我不会  我
I don't-- I mean--
你们能帮我做些什么吗
Can you guys build me something?
一些他不能控制我大脑的技术
Some kind of tech so he can't get into my head?
我不知道
I don't know.
威尔斯博士在这的话也许可以
Maybe if Dr. Wells were here.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你们每天都在想办法救人
Every day you guys figure out a way to help people.
闪电侠所有的超能力以及这里所有的设备
All of The Flash's powers and all of this equipment,
你们却救不了艾迪和我爸爸吗
and you can't save Eddie and my dad?
我们会想到办法的
We'll figure something out.
要快点
Fast.
爱瑞丝
Iris.
我脑海中一直回荡着那叫声
I can't get that sound out of my head.
我爸爸的尖叫声
My dad screaming.
他为什么坚持和你一起去下水道
Why did he insist on going down there with you?
他一直主张安全第一
He's always preaching about being safe,
可自己却总是义无反顾的以身涉险
but not once does he think about running into danger himself.
-爱瑞丝  -不  巴里
- Iris... - No, Barry.
他只是个普通警察
He's just a regular cop.
他不是超能力者  没有超能力
He is not some meta-human with superpowers.
他和你不一样
He's not you.
你说得对  他和我不一样
You're right, he's not me.
可这不是他的错
And this isn't his fault.
所有这些事都不是他的错
None of this is his fault.
没错  也许乔告诉我
Look, yes, maybe Joe told me
别告诉你我是闪电侠
not to tell you that I was The Flash,
可我没必要听他的话
but I didn't have to listen.
我本可以告诉你  上百次机会
I could've told you-- a hundred times
我本可以告诉你  可我却没说
I could've told you, and I didn't.
是的  我本该告诉你
Yes, I should've.
所以你有权生气
So you're right to be mad.
但别生你爸爸的气
But don't be mad at your dad.
生我的气
Be mad at me.
好
Okay.
好  那解释给我听
Okay, then explain to me
我以为我最了解的人怎么会
how the person I thought I knew better than anyone
对我隐瞒秘密
has been keeping secrets from me?
巨大的  改变人生的秘密
Big, life-changing secrets?
你本该是我最好的朋友  巴里
You were supposed to be my best friend, Barry.
我是你最好的朋友
I am your best friend.
你把你人生中最重要
How can you say that when the most important things
最重大的事情
in your life, the things that matter the most,
你应该与人分享的事情向我隐瞒
the things that you're supposed to share,
还好意思这么说
you kept all of them from me?
所有事你都瞒着我
You lied to me about everything.
我知道  爱瑞丝  我知道
I know, Iris. Look, I know.
但你也没有对我百分百的坦诚
But you haven't been entirely honest with me either.
什么  你在说什么
What? What are you talking about?
圣诞节时  我告诉你我对你的感觉
At Christmas, when I told you how I felt,
你说你没有同样的感觉
you said that you didn't feel the same way.
但我就是觉得
But I just feel like...
我不好说  也许事情没那么简单
I don't know, maybe things aren't that simple.
我说错了吗
Am I wrong?
我去看看西斯科和凯特琳
I'm gonna check on Cisco and Caitlin.
你知道他们会来找我的
You know they're going to find me.
而你  你也没有你想的那么聪明
And you. You're not as smart as you think you are.
是吗  我在我的时代就是个天才
Oh, really? 'Cause I'm a genius where I come from.
想想看跟你们这些古人比我得有多聪明
Imagine how smart that makes me here.
就因为你来自未来吗
'Cause you're from the future?
既然叫艾尔伯德
With a name like Eobard,
也该与众不同
I guess you'd have to be.
不  艾尔伯德是一个尊贵家族的
No, Eobard is a distinguished name
一位尊贵成员的尊贵名字
for a distinguished member of a distinguished family.
想到我的后代都像你一样疯狂就觉得烦躁
Depressing to think all of my descendants are as crazy as you.
不不不
Oh, no, no, no.
斯旺这一血脉
The Thawne bloodline is chock-
充满了有影响力的政治家  科学家
full of influential politicians, scientists,
企业领导者
captains of industry.
像你这样的失败者
Failures such as yourself
只是例外
are just the exception.
凭什么说我是个失败者
And what exactly makes me such a failure?
很难回答的问题  艾迪
Tough question, Eddie.
从哪说起呢
Where to start?
不如就从你的职业是警探说起吧
Oh, how about your career as a police detective?
极其的平凡
It's spectacularly uneventful.
是嘛  我们走着瞧
Yeah. Well, we'll see.
不  我们已经看到了
No, we have seen.
我看到了
I have seen.
我来自未来
I am from the future.
你是唯一一个被历史
And you are the only Thawne
遗忘的斯旺家族成员
to be all but forgotten by history.
浪费人生  枉为人啊
Waste of a life, waste of a man.
还有
And...
不
Oh, no.
你甚至都没得到那个女孩
You don't even get the girl.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
仔细看看  署名行
Observe, if you will, the byline.
闪电侠消失于危机中  作者爱瑞丝·韦斯特·艾伦
娶到爱瑞丝是巴里  不是你
Barry marries Iris and not you.
我们得把这只戒指
We're just gonna have to give this ring
给回艾格尼斯奶奶了
back to Grandma Agnes.
你  艾迪  用不上了
You, Eddie, won't be needing it.
反脑控制头带
An anti-telepathy strip.
它利用磁共振去中和
It uses magnetic resonance to neutralize
任何外部神经刺激
any foreign neurological stimulus.
所以它会保护巴里不受脑控制
So it'll protect Barry from being mind-controlled?
希望如此  但我们不知道
That's the hope, but we have no way of knowing
它是否有用
if it actually works.
会有用的
It'll work.
追踪器有反应了
The tracker just came online.
我们发现了古鲁德
We have Grodd's location.
爱瑞丝
Iris...
我想告诉你
I want you to know,
我那么多次想象你出现在这的画面
all the times I imagined you being here,
但不是像这样的
it was not like this.
救我爸爸回来
Get my dad back.
巴里  你预计到达时间是
Barry, what's your ETA?
好了
All right.
我已经到了
I'm in position.
等我的指令
Wait for my signal.
红色的是巴里吗
So the red, that's Barry?
-是的  -蓝色的呢
- Yes. - And the blue?
是古鲁德
Is Grodd.
好的  管他的
Okay. Here goes nothing.
蒸汽起作用了  古鲁德行动了
The steam's working. Grodd's on the move.
我不明白  计划是什么
I don't understand. What is the plan?
他把古鲁德引到
He's maneuvering Grodd into a tunnel
离巴里5.3英里远的隧道里去
5.3 miles from Barry.
然后巴里就能怎么做
So Barry can do what?
和对待钢梁的办法一样
Same thing he did to Girder.
超音速冲拳  宝贝
Supersonic punch, baby.
开始
Hit it!
超音速冲拳失败了
The supersonic punch failed.
来了
Here we go.
没事  西斯科
It's okay, Cisco.
头带管用
The headset's working.
好  试试快速拳打它
Yes. Okay, uh, try some speed punches on him.
没用
This isn't working.
好  你试试
Okay, what if you try--
巴里
Barry!
-巴里  -不
- Barry! - Oh, no.
头带断线了
The headset's offline.
听上去像是受到什么撞击
Sounded like it impacted with something.
人类  弱爆了
Human. Weak.
巴里的脑活动很不正常
Barry's brain activity is off the charts.
比上次要糟糕得多
It's way worse than last time.
他发生什么事了
What's happening to him?
古鲁德在对他使用精神打击
Grodd's attacking him psychically.
他被麻痹了
He's paralyzed.
临近警告
快啊  有辆路用列车就要开过来了
Come on. There's a service train coming.
拜托做点什么
Do something please!
我不能拦下那辆列车
I can't stop the train.
巴里  你得马上离开那
Barry, you have to get out of there now.
我们怎么做
What do we do?
巴里  听我说  好吗
Barry, listen to me, okay?
你得把注意力集中在我的声音上
You have to concentrate on my voice.
不论你发生了什么事
Whatever is happening to you,
你必须克服它
you have to fight it.
我知道你可以的  我知道你有多坚强
I know you can do this. I know how strong you are.
勇敢面对古鲁德
Stand up to Grodd.
你可以的
You can do this.
求你了
Please.
巴里  为了我
Barry, do it for me.
爱瑞丝
Iris.
乔
Joe.
巴里
Barry.
求求你  救我走吧
Please get me out of here.
巴里
Barry!
我这就带他回家
I'm bringing him home.
艾伦先生
Mr. Allen,
感谢你来看我
how nice of you to visit.
你还打算把我关多久
Exactly how long do you intend to keep me prisoner?
牢房控制终端
你的脑扫描一切正常
Your brain scan's normal,
也就是说  你已经脱离了古鲁德的控制
which means Grodd is no longer controlling you.
这个牢房是用来关押超能力者的
This prison is for meta-humans,
所以你可以走了
so you're free to go.
你终会遭到报应的
You will get what's coming to you eventually.
我并不认为我做错了  艾伦先生
I am not ashamed of my actions, Mr. Allen.
你也见识过这些超能力者的能耐
You've seen what these meta-humans are capable of.
很快  你的牢房就制不住他们了
Soon, your prison won't be enough.
不是所有超能力者都很危险
Not all meta-humans are dangerous.
你怕我知道你是闪电侠吗
Oh, you're afraid that I know you're The Flash?
别纠结了  几个月以来我一直知道
Don't get your tights in a twist; I've known for months.
我要真想收拾你  我早都动手了
I wanted to come after you, I would've done it by now.
但你觉得你用得上我
But you think you're gonna need me.
哈里森·威尔斯把我送给了那畜生
Harrison Wells turned me over to that beast.
他把我当提线木偶耍
He used me like a damn puppet.
你喜欢与否  我们有一个共同的敌人
So like it or not, we have a common enemy, you and I.
先失陪了  我得去抓大猩猩了
Now if you'll excuse me, I have a gorilla to hunt.
都说了让你别动
I said be still.
你断了三根肋骨
You have three fractured ribs.
我没事
I'll be fine.
爸  你得卧床休息
Dad, you need to rest.
真不敢相信  古鲁德竟变得如此暴力
I can't believe Grodd became so violent.
他的巢穴什么样
What was his lair like?
他吃香蕉吗  他喜欢《金刚》吗
Did he eat the banana? Does he like King Kong?
还是说他更喜欢《人猿星球》
He's more of a Planet of the Apes kind of ape?
非常可怕
Uh, terrifying.
不吃香蕉
No.
我没问
And I didn't ask.
我能不能单独和我女儿谈谈
Do you mind if I talk to my daughter alone?
我和猩猩在一起的时候
When I was with that gorilla,
我以为"我要死在这里了"
I thought, "I'm gonna die down here."
我脑海里全都是
And all I could think about
咱俩争吵的画面
was how you and me were in a fight.
爸  我很担心你  怕你出事
Dad, I was so afraid that something would happen to you.
从你出生那刻起  我的生命才有了意义
My life started when you were born,
有时候我对你深刻的爱
and sometimes my incredible love for you,
蒙蔽了我  我忘了...
it blinds me, and I forget--
我忘了你是一个很棒的年轻人
I forget what a brilliant young woman you are,
你有能力自己做决定
how you're capable of making your own decisions.
爸  我知道你所做的一切都出于爱
Daddy, I know that everything that you do is out of love.
既然爱我  就该告诉我真相
So love me enough to always tell me the truth.
-好吗  -好  我保证
- Yeah? - Deal. Deal.
好  来抱一个
Okay. Come here.
我错了
Oh, my bad.
抱歉
也许我们没抓住古鲁德是件好事
Maybe it's a good thing we didn't catch Grodd.
都不知道该把他关哪儿
Where would we put him?
管道监狱的设施可关不住
I mean, the Pipeline isn't exactly equipped
一个拥有超高智商和心电感应的大猩猩
to hold a super-intelligent, telepathic gorilla.
乔说古鲁德把威尔斯称作"父亲"
Joe mentioned that Grodd called Wells "Father."
一定是威尔斯让古鲁德来找我们的
And Wells must have ordered Grodd to come after us.
所以古鲁德才没杀乔
It's why Grodd didn't kill Joe.
我觉得乔说得对
I think Joe is right.
古鲁德做的一切都是想分散我们的注意力
Everything Grodd did, it was just to distract us.
你怎么了  你还好吗
What's going on? Are you okay?
就在想那个头带
Just thinking about this headset.
还不够牢靠
It wasn't strong enough.
你差点就被杀死了  哥们儿
You could've been killed out there, man.
没有  兄弟  你的装备管用了
No, dude, your tech worked,
而且它也证明我们不需要威尔斯
and it proved that we don't need Wells.
我们三人收拾了古鲁德  还救了乔
The three of us took on Grodd and rescued Joe.
只要我们三人合力  就没有办不成的事
Together, we can do anything.
其实  是我们四人
Actually, it was the four of us.
你怎么知道我在这儿
How did you know I was here?
这是你的据点
This is your spot.
是  这是个特别的地方
Yeah. It's a special spot.
这是我首次遇见闪电侠的地方
It's where I first met The Flash.
一直以来  你就站在
All those times, you were standing
我面前  而我却一无所知
right in front of me, and I had no idea.
我都不再了解你了
I don't even know you anymore.
爱瑞丝  当时在下水道里你跟我说的话
Iris, what you were saying to me when I was down the sewer...
你知道我为什么不害怕吗
You know why I wasn't afraid?
因为有你在
Because you were there.
即便我真的很恐慌  你的存在
Even though I really was scared, having you there
让我有勇气去面对古鲁德
is how I could stand up to Grodd.
我每次受挫
Every time I falter
每次犯错
or make a mistake,
只要想到你  我就又能重拾勇气
the thought of you is what picks me up
继续走下去
and keeps me going.
其实  我想说的是
Look, look, what I'm trying to say is,
就算你对我过去一年的生活
even though you didn't know everything
都一无所知  但这并不意味着
about my life this past year, that does not mean
你不是其中的一份子
that you weren't a part of it.
你一直都是
You were.
每一天都是
Every single day.
没有你
Without you,
就没有闪电侠
there wouldn't be The Flash.
我想了想你说的话
I've thought about what you said,
也许你说得对
and maybe you were right.
我的确一直在想你
I have been thinking about you,
想我们
about us.
但我不能再继续下去了
But I can't do that anymore.
艾迪是与我一同生活的人
Eddie is the man that I live with,
是我的爱人  而他还不知所踪
the man that I love, and he's still missing.
我懂
I know.
我会带他回来的
I'm gonna bring him back.
那之后呢
And after that?
我也不知道
I don't know.
我真的不知道
你现在又要做什么
So now what?
现在...
Now...
我拿到了钥匙
I have the key.
什么钥匙
The key to what?
该回家了
Time to go home.